Malleable Iron Fittings Company Records 1982.0004
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
Malleable Iron Fittings Company Records
undated, 1842-1962
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
1982.0004
83 Linear Feet
Branford, Connecticut, metal foundry, founded by Joseph Nason in 1841 as the Joseph Nason Company. Name changed to Walworth and Nason Company of Boston, Massachusetts, to manufacture equipment and install steam heating, and then to Malleable Iron Fittings Company in 1864, which produced malleable iron castings. Collection consists of administrative records, including production ledgers, melting reports, inventory and shipment books, order books, salesbooks, correspondence, and payroll books.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated to Archives & Special Collections in August 1982 by the New Haven Colony Historical Society.
History
The Malleable Iron Fittings Company (MIF) was originally incorporated in 1864. Its history, however, can be traced back to 1841 when twenty-six year old Joseph Nason, known as "the father of steam heating," established the Joseph Nason Company of New York to manufacture and sell pipe. Nason was patent holder of the globe and angle valve, the steam trap, cast and malleable taper joint pipe fittings, and the "radiator," which name he created.
In 1842, Nason and his brother-in-law, James J. Walworth of Boston, founded the Walworth and Nason Company of Boston (later known as the Walworth Company) to manufacture equipment for and install steam heating, then a novelty. Both men, however, wished to concentrate on a proposed line of malleable iron fittings, a difficult and expensive process. In 1864, Nason and Walworth took over the Totoket Company of Branford, Connecticut, with this objective in mind. (Totoket was the original name of the city of Branford). The Totoket Company was originally incorporated in 1854 by Elizur Rogers and Benjamin Hadley for the manufacture of hardware and other goods from wrought, cast, and malleable iron, scrap, and other metals. The Totoket plant was ideally situated between New York and Boston on a busy waterfront and next to a newly built railroad.
The new company was organized as the Malleable Iron Fittings Company. James C. Walworth became president of the company. Joseph Nason returned to New York to run Joseph Nason and Company, although he continued to cooperate closely with Walworth. The early MIF was essentially a subsidiary of the Walworth Company. It produced malleable iron castings that were shipped to the Walworth Company for finishing. The Walworth Company continued as a separate company while MIF grew and earned a reputation of its own.
Elizur Rogers of the Totoket Company remained with MIF. Two Danish immigrants, Emil C. Hammer and Thorvald F. Hammer, also joined the company. Emil C. Hammer was an experienced business administrator and the treasurer of Walworth Company. He became secretary and treasurer of MIF. Since James Walworth and Joseph Nason were more concerned with the interests of their own companies, day-to-day management of the MIF company was left in the hands of Emil C. Hammer. Thorvald F. Hammer was a highly skilled technician in foundry operations. It was descendents of Thorvald F. Hammer who would become most identified with the future growth and management of the company. Indeed, as late as 1962, the company was managed, headed and owned by one or several members of the Hammer, Walworth, or the Nason families.
The company, however, got off to a slow start. At first it was able to produce barely a half ton a day. But as the steam heating industry grew, so did MIF. The company soon earned a good reputation, and Joseph Nason was even called to Washington, D.C., and awarded a contract to heat the Capitol based on his innovative plans. The original founders were soon followed by the next generation. Upon the death of James C. Walworth, his son, Arthur C. Walworth, succeeded to the office of president. Arthur C. Walworth, however, never assumed an active participation in the company. Real management of the company fell upon the shoulders of Alfred E. Hammer, son of Thorvald Hammer. For many years Alfred E. Hammer was treasurer and manager, and in 1921, upon the death of Arthur C. Walworth, he became president. Under his guidance, the company made significant technical contributions to the iron industry as a whole, especially in the creation of superior castings. Soon the company was producing pipe fittings for buildings, industry and oil fields, marine and highway hardware, oil burners, and later pole hardware for the growing electric power industry.
Malleable iron, however, is limited in its applications to fittings and small castings, and in 1906, in order to meet the growing demand for larger and stronger castings, the company began manufacturing steel castings by the "converter" process. Such castings were in high demand by the government during World War I and the company expanded and renovated its facilities in order to meet it. Electric furnaces and additional annealing equipment were added, and by World War II the company's steel production was about equal to its malleable iron.
During the Depression, Thorvald F. Hammer II, grandson of Thorvald F. Hammer, acceded to the office of president upon the death of his father, Alfred E. Hammer, in 1935. Thorvald F. Hammer II quickly created a new Board of Directors, and embarked on a program of mechanization that put the plant on a mass production basis. Thorvald F. Hammer II also improved the working conditions of his labor force by installing modern showers, locker rooms, and dust elimination facilities for the personal comfort of his workers.
In 1915, MIF employed one thousand people and had an annual production capacity of 23,500 tons. It was the largest industry in Branford, Connecticut, and the largest malleable foundry in New England. Unlike other companies, which dominated small towns, the owners of MIF, however, exerted little control over the town of Branford. In 1935, in the midst of Depression, the company's labor force shrank to 500 employees. The company also experienced its first strike in 1935 when the CIO tried to organize the plant. The strike was successful and the plant was unionized. MIF eventually recovered from the Depression, and employment at the company hit a peak of 1,200 persons just before World War II. Continued plant mechanization after the war again contracted the work force to about 700 employees.
By the late 1950s, however, MIF profits began dwindling as it met with stiff competition from larger competitors who operated on a national basis. In 1962, Thorvald F. Hammer II resigned the presidency when a group of businessmen headed by Robert E. S. Thompson acquired control of the company. Thorvald F. Hammer II became Chairman of the Board. This development marked the first time MIF had not been headed by a member of the Hammer family.
In May 1963, MIF acquired the Bigelow Company of New Haven, a producer of steam boilers. MIF now embarked on a new modernization program of both its own facilities and those of the Bigelow Company. In July 1964, MIF continued its expansion when it consolidated with the Detroit Brass and Malleable Company. The pipe-fittings operations of Detroit Brass were moved to Branford, and this division was renamed the MIF-Detroit Pipe Fittings Division. The company's name was also changed to MIF Industries, Inc. The consolidation was expected to double the output of pipe-fittings thereby increasing overall sales volume and earnings potential.
These increased earnings were in turn to enable the company to continue its modernization program.
These hopes were not realized. The company's profits continued to decline, and in February 1969, MIF Industries was sold to Waltham Industries, a Delaware-based corporation, for $4.5 million. MIF Industries now joined a long list of other New Haven area businesses that sought relief from their economic woes through mergers with national companies. The company now became a subsidiary of Waltham Industries, and some of the metals productions division of Waltham Industries was moved to Branford. The move was expected to enable MIF to expand and modernize more rapidly. As many as 200 additional jobs were also expected to be created. Thorvald F. Hammer II retired as Chairman of the Board of Directors after forty-eight years of active service to the company. Robert E.S. Thompson resigned as president and became Chairman of the Board of Directors. Charles R. Schubert, a Vice President of Waltham Industries, was named president and chief executive officer.
The company, however, did not prosper. In 1969, losses totaled $3 million before taxes on sales of 11 million. Because of these losses, Waltham Industries ended manufacturing at MIF Industries and converted it into a distributor of its own products. By 1971, the payroll had been reduced to fifty employees, down from 750 employees in 1969. In 1971, Waltham Industries began selling off or removing most of the assets of MIF Industries. A court injunction obtained by the town of Branford halted this process because the company owed the town $300, 000 in back taxes. The 117 year manufacturing era of MIF was essentially at an end.
Custodial History
The collection was donated to the New Haven Colony Historical Society by Irving Rohinksy in 1981.
Scope and Content
The collection contains bound volumes of financial records arranged sequentially as well as administrative and financial records, regulations, blueprints, reports, patents and correspondence.
Notebooks; Publications (documents); Manuscripts (document genre); Correspondence; Blueprints (reprographic copies).; Personal papers; Connecticut (state); Twentieth century.; Branford (inhabited place); Financial Records; Industrialists; History; Boiler-makers; Iron industry and trade; Nason; Rogers; Walworth; Hammer; Hammer, Thorvald F.
- Series I: Bound volumes, undated, 1842-1962
  - [Shipment] Telegrams Sent, 1898-1900 (Volume 1)
  - Warbonds, 1917-1919 (Volume 2)
  - Warbonds, 1919-1920 (Volume 3)
  - Warbonds Ledger, 1918-1919 (Volume 4)
  - Medical Department Daily Log, 1959 January - August (Volume 5)
  - Medical Department Daily Log, 1959 September - 1960 March (Volume 6)
  - Medical Department Daily Log, 1960 March - November (Volume 7)
  - Medical Department Daily Log, 1960 November - 1962 February (Volume 8)
  - Production Ledger, 1883 (Volume 9)
  - Production Ledger, 1885 (Volume 10)
  - Production Ledger, 1886-1887 (Volume 11)
  - Production Ledger, 1888 (Volume 12)
  - Production Quality Control, 1890 August - October (Volume 13)
  - Production Quality Control, 1924-1929 (Volume 14)
  - Production Book: Fittings, 1929-1936 (Volume 15)
  - [Production:] Pattern Changes, 1898 (Volume 16)
  - Production Cost Book, 1912-1918 (Volume 17)
  - Production Book, 1912-1923 (Volume 18)
  - Production Record Book, 1915-1919 (Volume 19)
  - Cost of Shifting and Pouring, 1923-1931 (Volume 20)
  - Daily Malleable Melting Report, 1912-1915 (Volume 21)
  - Daily Malleable Melting Report, 1916-1918 (Volume 22)
  - Daily Malleable Melting Report, 1919-1920 (Volume 23)
  - Purchases, 1902 January - 1904 December (Volume 24)
  - Purchases, 1905 January - 1907 October (Volume 25)
  - Purchases, 1908 January - [1910] (Volume 26)
  - Purchases, 1910 January - 1912 May (Volume 27)
  - Iron Stock Account, 1930-1945 (Volume 28)
  - Inventory, 1888 (Volume 29)
  - Freight Receipt Book, 1898 (Volume 30)
  - Freight Receipt Book, 1901 (Volume 31)
  - Cars Received and Sent, 1899-1902 (Volume 32)
  - Cars Received and Sent, 1902-1904 (Volume 33)
  - Shipment Book, 1884 July - 1885 August (Volume 34)
  - Customer Index Book, undated (Volume 35)
  - Customer Index Ledger, 1902-1905 (Volume 36)
  - Customer Index Ledger, 1916-1917 (Volume 37)
  - Customer Index Ledger, 1917-1919 (Volume 38)
  - Orders, 1867-1872 (Volume 39)
  - Order Book, 1855-1865 (Volume 40)
  - Order Book, 1866-1878 (Volume 41)
  - Order Book, 1880-1881 (Volume 42)
  - Order Book, 1883-1884 (Volume 43)
  - Orders Book, 1884-1891 (Volume 44)
  - Hammers Co. Order Book, 1900-1916 (Volume 45)
  - Fittings Orders, 1906-1907 (Volume 46)
  - Boston Agency: Fittings Orders, 1906-1907 (Volume 47)
  - London: Fitting Orders, 1906 January - 1907 October (Volume 48)
  - New York Agency: Fitting Orders, 1905-1907 (Volume 49)
  - New York Agency: Fitting Orders, 1907 March - October (Volume 50)
  - Sales Ledger, 1866 December - 1879 June (Volume 51)
  - Sales Ledger, 1877 December - 1900 January (Volume 52)
  - Sales Balance Ledger, 1842-1892 (Volume 53)
  - Salesbook: U. S. W. Co., 1896-1901 (Volume 54)
  - I. Nathan Son: Sales Journal, 1866-1874 (Volume 55)
  - J. Nason & Co.: Sales Journal, 1865-1868 (Volume 56)
  - Salesbook, 1903 August - 1907 April (Volume 57)
  - Salesbook L, 1907 May - 1910 June (Volume 58)
  - Salesbook M, 1910 February - 1912 March (Volume 59)
  - Salesbook N, 1912 April - 1914 March (Volume 59a)
  - Salesbook, 1914 April - 1916 June (Volume 60)
  - Sales "P", 1916 July - 1918 September (Volume 61)
  - Salesbook Q, 1918 October - 1929 March (Volume 62)
  - Salesbook R, 1929 April - 1935 March (Volume 63)
  - Salesbook S, 1935 April - 1962 October (Volume 64)
  - Sales Ledger, 1902 March - 1905 May (Volume 65)
  - Sales Ledger, 1905 June - 1906 (Volume 66)
  - Sales Ledger, 1907 January - 1908 May (Volume 67)
  - Sales Ledger, 1909 June - 1910 (Volume 68)
  - Sales Ledger, 1911 January - 1914 May (Volume 69)
  - Sales Ledger, 1911 January - 1914 (?) (Volume 70)
  - Sales Ledger, 1914 July - 1917 (Volume 71)
  - Sales Ledger, 1917 January - 1919 (Volume 72)
  - Payroll Book, 1864 -1872 (Volume 73)
  - Payroll Book, 1880-1883 (Volume 74)
  - Payroll Book, 1883-1887 (Volume 75)
  - Payroll Book, 1887-1889 (Volume 76)
  - Payroll Book, 1889-1891 (Volume 77)
  - Payroll Book, 1891-1893 (Volume 78)
  - Payroll Book, 1893-1894 (Volume 79)
  - Payroll Book, 1894-1895 (Volume 80)
  - Payroll Book, 1896-1898 (Volume 81)
  - Payroll Book, 1898-1899 (Volume 82)
  - Payroll M, 1900 January - 1902 July (Volume 83)
  - Payroll Book, 1902-1904 (Volume 84)
  - Payroll Book, 1904-1906 (Volume 85)
  - Payroll Book, 1906-1908 (Volume 86)
  - Payroll, 1908-1909 (Volume 87)
  - Payroll, 1909-1910 (Volume 88)
  - Payroll, 1912-1913 (Volume 89)
  - Payroll, 1913-1914 (Volume 90)
  - Payroll, 1914-1916 (Volume 91)
  - Payroll, 1916-1917 (Volume 92)
  - Payroll, 1935-1937 (Volume 93)
  - Payroll book: Inspection Department, 1896-1897 (Volume 94)
  - Payroll book: Inspection Department, 1897-1898 (Volume 95)
  - Payroll book: Inspection Department, 1898-1899 (Volume 96)
  - Payroll book: Inspection Department, 1899-1900 (Volume 97)
  - Payroll book: Inspection Department, 1900 (Volume 98)
  - Payroll book: Inspection Department, 1900-1901 (Volume 99)
  - Payroll book: Inspection Department, 1901 (Volume 100)
  - Payroll book: Inspection Department, 1902 (Volume 101)
  - Payroll book: Inspection Department, 1903 (Volume 102)
  - Payroll book: Inspection Room, 1902-1903 (Volume 103)
  - Payroll book: Annealing Department, 1899-1900 (Volume 104)
  - Payroll book: Annealing Department, 1900-1901 (Volume 105)
  - Payroll book: Annealing Department, 1901-1902 (Volume 106)
  - Payroll book: Annealing Department, 1902 (Volume 107)
  - Payroll book: Annealing Department, 1902-1903 (Volume 108)
  - Payroll book: Annealing Department, 1903-1904 (Volume 109)
  - Payroll book: Galvanizing Department, 1900-1901 (Volume 110)
  - Payroll book: Galvanizing Department, 1901-1902 (Volume 111)
  - Payroll book: Casting and Shipping Department, 1902-1903 (Volume 112)
  - Payroll book: Foundry, 1901-1902 (Volume 113)
  - Payroll book: Supplementary Office and Foremen, 1899-1901 (Volume 114)
  - Payroll book: Front Shop, 1878-1879 (Volume 115)
  - Unidentified Payroll Book, 1903 October - 1904 November (Volume 116)
  - Unidentified Payroll Book, 1906 September - December (Volume 117)
  - Unidentified Payroll Book, 1906-1907 (Volume 118)
  - Labor Cost Book: Annealing Department, 1923-1934 (Volume 119)
  - Company Payrollbook, 1900-1901 (Volume 120)
  - Timebook [payroll], 1855 May - 1864 July (Volume 121)
  - Payroll Analysis 2, 1915-1920 (Volume 122)
  - Recapitalization Payroll, 1912-1913 (Volume 123)
  - Warranty & Quit Claims: Deeds, 1923-1936 (Volume 124)
  - Cash Ledger, 1872 July - 1879 December (Volume 125)
  - Cash Ledger, 1880 January - 1888 August (Volume 126)
  - Cash Ledger, 1888 September - 1894 June (Volume 127)
  - Cash Ledger, 1894 June - 1898 October (Volume 128)
  - Cash Ledger, 1898 November - 1901 September (Volume 129)
  - Cash Ledger, 1901 October - 1902 May (Volume 130)
  - Cash Ledger, 1902 January - 1904 April (Volume 131)
  - Cash Ledger, 1904 May - 1906 July (Volume 132)
  - Cash Ledger, 1906 August - 1908 October (Volume 133)
  - Cash Ledger, 1908 November - 1912 November (Volume 134)
  - Cash Ledger, 1912 December - 1918 October (Volume 135)
  - Cash Ledger, 1918 November - 1923 April (Volume 136)
  - Cash Ledger, 1923 May - 1927 May (Volume 137)
  - Cash Ledger, 1927 June - 1931 June (Volume 138)
  - Cash Ledger, 1931 July - 1935 June (Volume 139)
  - Cash Ledger, 1939 January - 1940 November (Volume 140)
  - Cash Book, 1867 October - 1876 June (Volume 141)
  - Cash Book, 1872-1874 (Volume 142)
  - Cash Book, 1886 March - 1903 April (Volume 143)
  - Cash Book, 1903 May - 1913 December (Volume 144)
  - Cashbook, 1908-1919 (Volume 145)
  - Cashbook, 1914 January - 1917 December (Volume 146)
  - Cashbook, 1919-1928 (Volume 147)
  - Cashbook, 1939-1957 (Volume 148)
  - Cash Advanced to Workmen, 1873-1877 (Volume 149)
  - Bankbook: Second National Bank of New England with E. C. Hammer, 1875-1880 (Volume 150)
  - Bankbook: Second National Bank of New Haven: an account with E. C. Hammer, Treasurer, 1880-1883 (Volume 151)
  - Bankbook: Second National Bank of New Haven, CT, 1885-1887 (Volume 152)
  - Bankbook, 1890 October - 1891 December (Volume 153)
  - Bankbook: First National Bank, 1892-1893 (Volume 154)
  - Bank Deposits, 1906-1921 (Volume 155)
  - Petty Cash Book, 1897-1901 (Volume 156)
  - Check Register, 1897-1898 (Volume 157)
  - Invoices Credit, 1916-1917 (Volume 158)
  - Cashbook: Blackstone Memorial Library, 1915 January - 1933 September (Volume 159)
  - I. Nathan Son & Co. Daybook, 1876 April - 1882 February (Volume 160)
  - Hammer & Co. Daybook, 1882 March - 1884 November (Volume 161)
  - Daybook, 1854 March - 1863 June (Volume 162)
  - Daybook, 1864 April - 1871 June (Volume 163)
  - Daybook, 1872 July - 1878 February (Volume 164)
  - Daybook, 1878 March - 1883 April (Volume 165)
  - Daybook, 1883 May - 1884 February (Volume 166)
  - Daybook, 1884 March - 1889 September (Volume 167)
  - Daybook, 1889 October - 1891 June (Volume 168)
  - Daybook, 1899 May - 1901 July (Volume 169)
  - Daybook, 1901 August - 1903 July (Volume 170)
  - Journal, 1902 June - 1903 November (Volume 171)
  - Journal, 1903 December - 1906 October (Volume 172)
  - Journal, 1906 November - 1910 May (Volume 173)
  - Journal, 1910 January - 1913 September (Volume 174)
  - Journal, 1913 October - 1917 March (Volume 175)
  - Journal, 1917 April - 1920 May (Volume 176)
  - Journal, 1920 January - 1923 April (Volume 177)
  - Journal, 1923 May - 1925 December (Volume 178)
  - Journal, 1926 January - 1928 May (Volume 179)
  - Journal, 1928 June - 1931 February (Volume 180)
  - Journal, 1931 March - 1933 November (Volume 181)
  - Journal, 1933 December - 1936 July (Volume 182)
  - Journal, 1936 August - 1938 September (Volume 183)
  - Journal, 1938 October - 1940 June (Volume 184)
  - Ledger A, 1864-1872 (Volume 185)
  - Ledger B, 1873-1879 (Volume 186)
  - Ledger D, 1884-1891 (Volume 187)
  - Ledger E, 1882-1896 (Volume 188)
  - Ledger, 1896-1899 (Volume 189)
  - Ledger, 1900-1902 (Volume 190)
  - General Ledger, undated (Volume 191)
  - Hammer & Co. Ledger, 1909-1913 (Volume 192)
  - Hammer & Co. Ledger, 1909-1917 (Volume 193)
  - Ledger, 1855-1862 (Volume 194)
  - Ledger, 1891-1901 (Volume 195)
  - Ledger, 1895-1908 (Volume 196)
  - Executive's Notebook, 1906 (Volume 197)
  - Administrative Charges Ledger, 1929-1935 (Volume 198)
  - Tax Ledger, 1911-1917 (Volume 199)
  - Trial Balance Ledger, 1921-1932 (Volume 200)
  - Letterbook # 1, 1864 April - 1867 April (Volume 201)
  - Letterbook # 2, 1867 April - 1871 March (Volume 202)
  - Letterbook # 3, 1871 March - 1874 October (Volume 203)
  - Letterbook # 4, 1874 October - 1877 December (Volume 204)
  - Letterbook # 5, 1877 December - 1880 June (Volume 205)
  - Letterbook # 6, 1880 July - 1882 November (Volume 206)
  - Letterbook # 7, 1882 November - 1884 July (Volume 207)
  - Letterbook # 8, 1884 July - 1885 June (Volume 208)
  - Letterbook # 10, 1886 March - October (Volume 209)
  - Letterbook # 11, 1886 October - 1887 April (Volume 210)
  - Letterbook # 12, 1887 April - November (Volume 211)
  - Letterbook # 13, 1887 November - 1888 July (Volume 212)
  - Letterbook # 15, 1889 August - 1890 May (Volume 213)
  - Letterbook # 16, 1890 May - November (Volume 214)
  - Letterbook # 17, 1890 November - 1891 May (Volume 215)
  - Letterbook # 18, 1891 May - December (Volume 216)
  - Letterbook # 19, 1891 December - 1892 May (Volume 217)
  - Letterbook # 20, 1892 May - October (Volume 218)
  - Letterbook # 21, 1892 October - 1893 March (Volume 219)
  - Letterbook # 22, 1893 March - July (Volume 220)
  - Letterbook # 23, 1893 July - December (Volume 221)
  - Letterbook # 24, 1893 December - 1894 April (Volume 222)
  - Letterbook # 25, 1894 April - September (Volume 223)
  - Letterbook # 26, 1894 September - December (Volume 224)
  - Letterbook # 27, 1894 December - 1895 March (Volume 225)
  - Letterbook # 28, 1895 March - June (Volume 226)
  - Letterbook # 29, 1895 June - August (Volume 227)
  - Letterbook # 30, 1895 August - November (Volume 228)
  - Letterbook # 31, 1895 November - 1896 January (Volume 229)
  - Letterbook # 32, 1896 January - April (Volume 230)
  - Letterbook # 33, 1896 April - June (Volume 231)
  - Letterbook # 34, 1896 June - September (Volume 232)
  - Letterbook # 35, 1896 September - December (Volume 233)
  - Letterbook # 37, 1897 February - May (Volume 234)
  - Letterbook # 38, 1897 May - August (Volume 235)
  - Letterbook # 39, 1897 August - October (Volume 236)
  - Letterbook # 42, 1898 March - June (Volume 237)
  - Letterbook, 1867 October - 1868 March (Volume 238)
  - Letterbook, 1877 April - 1886 April (Volume 239)
  - Letterbook, 1886 April - 1891 March (Volume 240)
  - Letterbook, 1895 January - 1897 June (Volume 241)
  - Letterbook, 1897 June - 1899 August (Volume 242)
  - Letterbook, 1899 August - 1901 November (Volume 243)
  - Letterbook, 1901 December - 1903 August (Volume 244)
  - Letterbook, 1903 August - 1905 April (Volume 245)
  - Letterbook, 1905 April - 1906 October (Volume 246)
  - Letterbook, 1906 October - December (Volume 247)
  - Letterbook, 1882 January - 1889 October (Volume 248)
  - Letterbook, 1884 January - 1887 April (Volume 249)
  - Detroit Assets Purchased, undated (Volume 250)
- Series II: Records, undated, 1878-1939
  - War regulations, undated (Box 1)
  - Income Tax Returns, undated (Box 2)
  - Personnel Files, undated (Box 3)
  - Administrative Files, undated (Box 4, Box 5)
  - Projections, undated (Box 6)
  - Reports and Studies, undated (Box 7)
  - Bundles, undated (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 9, Box 10)
  - Patent Certificates, undated (Box 11)
  - Blueprints, undated (Box 12)
  - Contracts and Agreements, undated (Box 13)
  - Production Information, Legal Information, undated (Box 14)
  - Files, undated (Box 15)
  - Blueprints, Journals and Ledgers, undated (Box 16)